Yohan Franca

<u>linkedin.com/in/yohanalexander</u> <u>github.com/yohanalexander</u>

Software engineer who helped Uber to migrate a 7 Billion dollar business to deliver groceries on demand, while keeping user retention. Passionate to build a magical user experience, scale systems up, and ship reliable applications.

Work Experience

Software Engineer Uber 2023–Present

Grocery and Retail Team

• Increased monthly active users and annual GB through targeted campaigns and enhanced product visibility.

Remote, Brazil

- Reduced infrastructure costs by millions porting systems from acquired companies into Uber's primary data centers.
- Leveraged A/B testing to gradually launch features and analyze key business performance metrics.

Software Engineer Cornershop 2021–2023

Shopper Experience Team

Remote, Brazil

- Improved time arrival estimations by creating an optimized caching mechanism as a fallback from data models queried via network APIs.
- Implemented asynchronous tasks to perform batch operations on the database based on the processing of data uploaded on internal tools via CSV files.
- Leveraged knowledge of state machines to implement a rules engine based on a DSL that automatically solved alerts related to the operation.

Software Developer PagueON 2020–2021

Payments Account Team

Aracaju, SE

payment of utility bills.

- Helped to expand the customer base by implementing digital bank accounts, debit cards, payment of utility bills, and bank slips.
- Prepared the microservices infrastructure to handle thousands of requests in an internal network based on protocol buffers exposed via an API Gateway.
- Established end-to-end testing using Postman, and CI/CD using Docker and Jenkins.
- Leveraged AWS cloud knowledge using buckets to store assets.

Software Developer Intern University of Sergipe

Aracaju, SE

2019-2020

• Developed scientific computing software using Python for astronomical data analysis techniques.

Education and Certifications

• **B.Sc. Computer Science,** Federal University of Sergipe, São Cristóvão.

2018-2022

Technologies and Languages

Languages: (proficient) Go, Python, (familiar) Java, C++
Technologies: SQL, Redis, Git, Docker, Linux, Bash, AWS
Other: Data structures and algorithms, Microservices